Guide to the Rice University Program Council records, 1962-2014 UA 028
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Program Council records
1962-2014
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice Program Council
UA 028
5 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
This record group includes correspondence and event planning documents from the Student Center Board, as well as the daily business, publicity, meeting minutes, and memorabilia of the Rice Program Council (RPC).
Historical Note
The Student Association (SA) created the Rice Program Council (RPC) in 1971. It replaced the SA's Student Center Board, the Forum, and the Social Committee to become the official programming arm of the SA. Since its inception, RPC has managed Beer Bike, Esperanza, Rondelet, and other events. As of 2014, they plan all of the above plus Screw Your Roommate, Crush Party, various Willy Week events, and the Welcome Back Concert.
Scope and Contents
This record group charts the history of the Student Center Board and the Rice Program Council. There are minutes, calendars, contracts, and event glassware.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Boxes 1-7 stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586. Box 8 stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Julie Neisler in 2014.
Related Materials
See also Beer-Bike records, 1957-2014 (UA 095), Woodson Research Center
Accruals Note
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Index Terms
Subjects
College students -- Texas; Social life and customs; Universities and colleges
Document Types
letters (correspondence); T-shirts; minutes (administrative records); financial records; programs (documents); photographs; memorabilia; clippings (information artifacts)
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University; Rice Program Council
- Series I: Student Center Board, 1962-1971, 176607
  - Art Events, 1969-1970; 176608 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Athletic Events, 1970; 176609 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Charity Events, n.d.; 176610 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Constitution/Mission, n.d.; 176611 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Events Calendar, October 1970; 176612 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Film Events, 1969-1970, n.d.; 176613 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Holiday Events, 1967, 1970, n.d.; 176614 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1962-1963, 1970-1971; 176615 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Musical Events, 1965-1966, 1970, n.d.; 176616 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Officers, 1970/1971; 176617 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Social Events, 1969-1970; 176618 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: General, 1971-2014, 176619
  - Budget, 1971-1979; 176639 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Budget, 1980-1989; 176640 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Budget, 2000-2008; 176642 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Committee Reports, 1975/1976, 2000; 176623 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Constitution, 1971, 1994/1995, 2006, n.d.; 176624 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1976; 176645 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Council, 1971-1979; 176646 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Council, 1980-1989; 176625 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Council, 1990-1999; 176626 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Council, 2000-2002; 176627 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Forms, n.d.; 176655 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "A Guide to excitement, fulfillment, and pleasure", 1979/1980; 176656 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Guidelines and Policies, 1981/1982, n.d.; 176657 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Handouts, 2007/2008; 176628 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Insurance, 2002; 176629 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Interviews, 1976, n.d.; 176647 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - News Clippings, 1971-; 176648 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Programming Packet, 1995, 1999, n.d.; 176632 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Proposal Committee - Rice Memorial Center Space Planning, 1972; 176658 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Reform Committee, n.d.; 176633 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Retreat, 1995-1999; 176634 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Retreat, 2000-2009; 176635 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Retreat, 2010-; 176636 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Rice People's Guide to Houston", 1978/1979; 176637 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Service Committee, 1971-1976; 176664 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Survey, 1973; 176638 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Tax, 1976; 176649 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Workshop, 1976; 176650 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series III: Events, 1971-2012, 176659
  - Subseries A: General, 176660
    - Calendar of Events, 1971-1979; 176665 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Calendar of Events, 1980-1989; 176666 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Calendar of Events, 1990-1999; 176667 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Calendar of Events, 2000-2009; 176668 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Event Evaluation, n.d.; 176669 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Events, 1971-1979; 176670 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Events, 1980-1989; 176671 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Events, 1990-1999; 176672 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Events, 2000-2009; 176673 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Events, 2010-; 176674 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Films, 1974, n.d.; 176675 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Fine Arts Events, 1974, n.d.; 176676 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Formals, 2007/2008; 176677 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Party Guidelines, 1979; 176678 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Political Events, 1971-1976, 1984; 176679 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Subseries B: Esperanza, 176661
    - 1993, 176680 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1998, 176681 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 2001, 176682 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 2002, 176683 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 2003, 176684 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 2004, 176685 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 2005, 176686 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 2006, 176687 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Subseries C: Passport to Houston, 176662
    - General, 2005-2008; 176688 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Alley Theater, 2007; 176689 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Beyond the Hedges, 2008; 176690 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Brilliant Lectures, 2006-2007; 176691 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Buffalo Bayou, 2005-2006; 176692 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Da Camera, 2005-2008; 176693 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Dance Salad, 2005-2008; 176694 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Discover Houston Tours, 2005-2007; 176695 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Ensemble Theatre, 2005-2010; 176696 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Events, 2005-2006; 176697 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Health Museum, 2006-2007; 176698 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Hedgehopper, 2005-2006; 176699 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - The Heritage Society, 2006-2007; 176700 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Houston Aeros, 2006; 176701 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Houston Astros, 2009-2010; 176702 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Houston Ballet, 2006-2008; 176703 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Houston Grand Opera, 2004-2008; 176704 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Houston Rockets, 2009-2011; 176705 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Houston Symphony, 2005-2008; 176706 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Houston Wilderness, 2005-2007; 176707 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Houston Zoo, 2005-2007; 176708 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Main Stree Theater, 2005-2007; 176709 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - The Menil Collection, 2010; 176710 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Mercury Baroque, 2006-2007; 176711 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Miller Outdoor Theatre, 2008; 176712 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Museum of Fine Arts (photographs), 2012; 176713 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Museum of Natural Science, 2005-2010; 176714 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - O-Week Passport Night, 2007-2009; 176715 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Rice Nights, 2005-2007; 176716 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Scavenger Hunt, 2007; 176717 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Society for the Performing Arts, 2006-2007; 176718 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Spacetaker, 2005-2006; 176719 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Subseries D: Rondelet, 176663
    - New Rondelet Policy, 176720 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1a)
    - 1971, 176721 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 1972, 176722 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 1974, 176723 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1975, 176724 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 1976, 176725 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 1992, 176726 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1994, 176727 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 1999, 176728 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 2002, 176729 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 2003, 176730 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 2004, 176731 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - 2005, 176732 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - 2006, 176733 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Series IV: Minutes and Agenda, 1973-2009, 176734
  - 1973/1974, 176735 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 1974/1975, 176736 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 1976/1977, 176737 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 1978/1979, 176738 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 1980/1981, 176739 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 1981/1982, 176740 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - 1983/1984, 176741 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - 1984/1985, 176742 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 1985/1986, 176743 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 1986/1987, 176744 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 1987/1988, 176745 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 1988/1989, 176746 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - 1989/1990, 176747 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - 1990/1991, 176748 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - 1991/1992, 176749 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - 1992/1993, 176750 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 1993/1994, 176751 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 1994/1995, 176752 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 1995/1996, 176753 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 1996/1997, 176754 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1997/1998, 176755 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1998/1999, 176756 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1999/2000, 176757 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 2000/2001, 176758 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 2001/2002, 176759 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 2002/2003, 176760 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 2003/2004, 176761 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 2004/2005, 176762 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 2005/2006, 176763 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 2006/2007, 176764 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 2007/2008, 176765 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 2008/2009, 176766 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Series V: Media, 2002-2008, 176767
  - RPC - documents (CD), 2002-2008; 176771 (Box 7, Item -)
  - Passport to Houston - documents (CD), 2005-2008; 176772 (Box 7, Item -)
  - Museum of Fine Arts "Passport to Houston Event" - images (CD), 2005; 176773 (Box 7, Item -)
  - Museum of Fine Arts - images (CD), 2005; 176774 (Box 7, Item -)
  - Houston Museum of Natural Science - images - (CD), 2005; 176775 (Box 7, Item -)
  - Houston Symphony - images (CD), 2005; 176776 (Box 7, Item -)
  - Houston Zoo - images by Jeff Fitlow (CD), 2006; 176777 (Box 7, Item -)
  - Passport to Houston pamphlet (CD), 2006; 176778 (Box 7, Item -)
  - Downtown Aquarium - Families Weekend - images by Jeff Fitlow (CD), 2006; 176779 (Box 7, Item -)
  - Houston Museum of Natural Science - images (CD), 2007; 176780 (Box 7, Item -)
  - Museum of Fine Arts and Museum of Natural Science - images by Jeff Fitlow (DVD), 2007-2008; 176781 (Box 7, Item -)
- Series VI: Memorabilia, 1995-2011, 176768
  - Pablo Neruda quote on blue sign, 1971/1972; 176806 (Box 7, Item -)
  - Subseries A: T-Shirts, 176769
    - Screw Yer Roommate, 2011; 176782 (Box 7, Item -)
    - A&E Representative, n.d.; 176783 (Box 7, Item -)
    - College Representative, n.d.; 176784 (Box 7, Item -)
    - RPC logo, n.d.; 176785 (Box 7, Item -)
    - Screw Your Roommate, n.d.; 176786 (Box 7, Item -)
    - Welcome Back Day, 2013 (Box 7, Folder -)
  - Subseries B: Glassware/Plasticware, 176770
    - A Little Shot of Jazz - Esperanza - Shot glass, 1995; 176787 (Box 8, Item -)
    - Cabaret - Esperanza - Beer mug, 176788 (Box 8, Item -)
    - The Formal Formerly Known as... - Rondelet - Shot glass, 1997; 176789 (Box 8, Item -)
    - Esperanza - Brandy snifter, 1997; 176790 (Box 8, Item -)
    - The Rites of Spring - Rondelet - Shot glass, 1998; 176791 (Box 8, Item -)
    - Balmoral - Esperanza - Beer mug, 1998; 176792 (Box 8, Item -)
    - Sabrosura - Rondelet - Tumbler, 1999; 176793 (Box 8, Item -)
    - "Sous Les Etoiles" - Esperanza - Champagne flute, 1999; 176794 (Box 8, Item -)
    - "A Night in Old Houston" - Rondelet - Martini glass, 2000; 176795 (Box 8, Item -)
    - Love Shack - Rondelet - Shot glass, 2001; 176796 (Box 8, Item -)
    - A Masquerade Ball - Rondelet - Cordial glass, 176797 (Box 8, Item -)
    - Field of Dreams - Esperanza - Beer mug, 2002; 176798 (Box 8, Item -)
    - Bucky Ball - Rondelet - Champagne flute, 2003; 176799 (Box 8, Item -)
    - E³ - Esperanza - Weizen glass, 2003; 176800 (Box 8, Item -)
    - Cosmopolitan at the Metropolitan - Rondelet - Martini glass, 2004; 176801 (Box 8, Item -)
    - Breakfast at Tiffany's - Esperanza - Shot glass, 2004; 176802 (Box 8, Item -)
    - Hard Rock - Rondelet - Shot glass, 2005; 176803 (Box 8, Item -)
    - RPC logo - Double bubble shot glass, n.d.; 176804 (Box 8, Item -)
    - Screw Your Roommate - Plastic cup, n.d.; 176805 (Box 8, Item -)
  - Sunglasses, ca. 2012 (Box 7, Item -)